{
    "id": "5163b761b6214c0f8473ba4e66335e1e",
    "title": "Though, although, even though, even if, in spite of or despite",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I enjoyed the party ................................. having a headache.",
            "description": "Both despite and in spite of are possible here. They are both prepositions and can be followed by a noun or an -ing form. Though and although are conjunctions and should be followed by clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "despite",
                "though",
                "although",
                "in spite of"
            ],
            "correct": 3,
            "id": "d92f1e45d460408c82af64d3d911bdd3"
        },
        {
            "question": ".......................... he was there, he did not acknowledge my presence.",
            "description": "Though and although are conjunctions and should be followed by clauses. In spite of and despite are prepositions.",
            "answers": [
                "Either though or although",
                "Despite",
                "In spite",
                "Despite or in spite of"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "dd793843addd45b7b48c253139adb381"
        },
        {
            "question": "......................... she was angry, she said nothing.",
            "description": "Though and although are conjunctions and need to be followed by clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "Either though or although",
                "Either in spite of or despite",
                "In spite of"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "ad41df1db5ec49e592723d1380b5c6c9"
        },
        {
            "question": "She passed her exam ............................ having a bad teacher.",
            "description": "Despite is a preposition and can be followed by a noun or -ing form. In spite is not a preposition. The correct expression is in spite of.",
            "answers": [
                "despite of",
                "in spite",
                "despite"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "81ebf8d24e7347dc8df044d6472a3be1"
        },
        {
            "question": "......................... the train was late, I managed to arrive on time.",
            "description": "Even though refers to the past even if refers to the future.",
            "answers": [
                "Despite",
                "Even though",
                "Even if"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "279ddd144dba45c8b9379e29b22b1a0b"
        },
        {
            "question": "I will do it ........................... it kills me.",
            "description": "Even if refers to the future. Even though refers to the past. ",
            "answers": [
                "even though",
                "though",
                "even if"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "f976fe45364a4d0f9bd04640ccd3a355"
        },
        {
            "question": "............................. his disability, he works very hard.",
            "description": "The expressions though, although, even though and even if are all conjunctions and should be followed by a clause. In spite of is a preposition. It is followed by a noun or ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "In spite of",
                "Although",
                "Even though"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "2d355291633742c9b98ac85dca5434f2"
        },
        {
            "question": ".................................... I didn't understand a word, I kept smiling.",
            "description": "Though and even though have similar meanings. Even though is more emphatic. ",
            "answers": [
                "Though",
                "Even though",
                "Either though or even though"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "c2313173ef384c75a82af35d1ccd1456"
        },
        {
            "question": "The strongest argument, ............................., is political not economic.",
            "description": "Though can be used as an adverb and it means 'however'. Even though and although cannot be used with this meaning. ",
            "answers": [
                "even though",
                "although",
                "though"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "eaf3cbd37bd34b2fb9a9c1e3303817a8"
        },
        {
            "question": "............................ I don't agree with his views, I think he is honest.",
            "description": "Though, although and even though have the same meaning. Even though is more emphatic than though or although.",
            "answers": [
                "Though",
                "Although",
                "Even though",
                "All of the above"
            ],
            "correct": 3,
            "id": "89ab49d977ba4985b5715800f13a479e"
        },
        {
            "question": ".............................. she worked very hard, she didn't get the promotion.",
            "description": "Despite is a preposition and cannot be followed by a clause. Even if refers to the future. ",
            "answers": [
                "Despite",
                "Though",
                "Even if"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "e41cdb78e8044e6689e0b0d70fb1ca32"
        },
        {
            "question": "............................... of performing well in the interview, she didn't get the job.",
            "description": "Even if and even though are conjunctions followed by clauses.",
            "answers": [
                "In spite of",
                "Even if",
                "Even though"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "148643b3674b48308fe2883f0ebb7bb6"
        }
    ]
}